Guide to the Elena Wilson Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1931-1979; Series I; 3.13; (8 boxes)
  - Newberry Library, 1973-74 (Box 5, Folder 197)
  - Nichols, Mike, 1972 Jun (Box 5, Folder 198)
  - Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1972 Jun 15 (Box 5, Folder 199)
  - Novak, Michael Paul, 1974-75 (Box 5, Folder 200)
  - O'Donnell, Thomas Francis, 1972-74 (Box 5, Folder 201)
  - Oliver, Edith, 1972, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 202)
  - Olson, Stanley, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 203)
  - O'Neill, William L., 1977-78 (Box 5, Folder 204)
  - Orwell, Sonia, 1972-74 (Box 5, Folder 205)
  - Ouroussow, Eugenie, 1972, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 206)
  - Oxford University Press, 1972-74 (Box 5, Folder 207)
  - Pcolar, Mary
  - Peck, John B.
  - Peper, George F., 1973, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 208)
  - Perelman, S. J. (Sidney Joseph), 1974 Dec 23 (Box 5, Folder 209)
  - Phaidon Press, 1975-78, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 210)
  - Pipes, Richard, 1972 Aug 2 (Box 5, Folder 211)
  - Porter Katherine Anne, 1975 Jan 17 (Box 5, Folder 212)
  - Praz, Mario, 1973 Feb 18 (Box 5, Folder 213)
  - Princeton University, 1972 Jun 28 (Box 5, Folder 214)
  - Princeton University Library, 1973-77, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 215)
  - Princeton University Press, 1977 Jan-Feb (Box 5, Folder 216)
  - Pritchett, V. S. (Victor Sawdon), 1972-75 (Box 5, Folder 217)
  - Radowitz, Carol von, 1972-79 (Box 5, Folder 218)
  - Radowitz, Tit von, 1972-79 (Box 5, Folder 219)
    Includes photograph of von Radowitz, Alexander
  - Ramey, Phillip, 1976 Mar 6 (Box 5, Folder 220)
  - Reed, Joseph W., 1975 May 2 (Box 5, Folder 221)
  - Reeve, Franklin, 1972, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 222)
  - Richards, I. A. (Ivor Armstrong), 1972 Jun (Box 5, Folder 223)
  - Rorem, Ned, 1974 Apr 26 (Box 5, Folder 224)
  - Rothschild, Judith, 1978 Jul (Box 5, Folder 225)
  - Rullman, Margaret E., 1972-76, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 226)
  - Sahl, Hans, 1972, Jun (Box 5, Folder 227)
  - Salmi, Sylvia, 1972 Jul 4 (Box 5, Folder 228)
  - Sayre, Nora, 1975 May-Jun (Box 5, Folder 229)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr., 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 230)
  - Schouvaloff, Elisabeth, 1972-74 (Box 5, Folder 231)
  - Schroeter, James, 1972 Aug-Oct (Box 5, Folder 232)
  - Schwartz, Sanford, 1979 May 9 (Box 6, Folder 233)
  - Segal, Erich, 1974 Sep 1 (Box 6, Folder 234)
  - Seldes, Marian, 1972-73 (Box 6, Folder 235)
  - Seyersted, Per, 1975 Jan 19 (Box 6, Folder 236)
  - Sharp, Malcolm, 1972-73 (Box 6, Folder 237)
    Envelope only
  - Shawn, William, 1972 Jun 14 (Box 6, Folder 238)
    See also: The New Yorker, box 5, folder 196
  - Sheed, Wilfrid (from Mellon, Evelyn Emig), 1973 Jul 15 (Box 6, Folder 239)
  - Spender, Stephen, 1973 Mar 7 (Box 6, Folder 240)
  - Spindler, Elizabeth Carroll, 1975, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 241)
  - Stafford, Jean, 1972, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 242)
  - Stanford University Libraries, 1974 Apr-May (Box 6, Folder 243)
  - State University of New York at Buffalo Library, 1973-74 (Box 6, Folder 244)
  - Steegmuller, Francis, 1972-75 (Box 6, Folder 245)
  - Strachan, Pat
  - Straus, Dorothea, 1972 Jun (Box 6, Folder 246)
  - Straus, Roger W.
  - Struve, Gleb, 1974-79 (Box 6, Folder 247)
  - Studds, Gerry E., 1979 Apr 23 (Box 6, Folder 248)
  - Sutherland, Donald, 1973 Jan-Dec (Box 6, Folder 249)
  - Tate, Allen, 1977 Oct 7 (Box 6, Folder 250)
  - Thoby-Marcelin, Eva, 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 251)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1974 Aug 26 (Box 6, Folder 252)
  - Thornton, D. W., 1931, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 253)
  - Thornton, Daphne Sellar, 1972, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 254)
  - Thornton, Henry H. M., 1955, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 255)
  - Thurber, Helen, 1974 Oct 16 (Box 6, Folder 256)
  - Tierney, Helen May Gould
    See: Gould, Helen May, box 4, folder 122
  - Todd, Charles L., 1972 Aug-Oct (Box 6, Folder 257)
  - Turner, Arlin, 1974 Oct 24 (Box 6, Folder 258)
  - University of Chicago Library, 1973 Mar-Apr (Box 6, Folder 259)
  - University of Iowa Library, 1974, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 260)
  - University of Pennsylvania Charles Patterson Van Pelt Library, 1973-74 (Box 6, Folder 261)
  - University of Texas Humanities Research Center, 1973-76 (Box 6, Folder 262)
  - University of Virginia Library, 1973-74 (Box 6, Folder 263)
  - Untermeyer, Louis, 1974 Oct 18 (Box 6, Folder 264)
  - Updike, John, 1976 Feb 27 (Box 6, Folder 265)
  - Viereck, Peter Robert Edwin, 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 266)
  - Vogue, 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 267)
  - Wain, John, 1974-77 (Box 6, Folder 268)
  - Walker, Adelaide, 1977 Sep 24 (Box 6, Folder 269)
  - Walker, Charles Rumford, 1978 Apr 3 (Box 6, Folder 270)
  - Ward, Aileen, 1972, 1977, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 271)
  - Warren, Robert Penn, 1972, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 272)
  - Warshow, Paul, 1973-74 (Box 6, Folder 273)
  - Weeks, Edward, 1972 Jun 18 (Box 6, Folder 274)
  - Weill, Cléanthe Kimball Carr, 1972, Dec 4 (Box 6, Folder 275)
  - Wensinger, Arthur S., 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 276)
  - Werner, M. R. (Morris Robert), 1972, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 277)
  - Wheelock, John Hall, 1974 Apr 12 (Box 6, Folder 278)
  - White, Katharine Sergeant Angell, 1972 Jun-Dec (Box 6, Folder 279)
  - Wilder, Thornton, 1974 Feb-Apr (Box 6, Folder 280)
  - Wilson, Angus, 1972, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 281)
  - Wilson, Edmund, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 282-286)
  - Wilson, Edmund, 1947-61 (Box 7, Folder 287-295)
  - Wilson, Edmund, 1961-69, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 296-300)
  - Wilson, Edmund (Box 8, Folder 301-302)
  - Wilson, Helen Miranda, 1960-79, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 303)
  - Wilson, Marcia Ruiz, 1972 Jul-Aug (Box 8, Folder 304)
  - Wilson, Marcia Ruiz (to Wilson, Helen Miranda), 1972 Aug 20 (Box 8, Folder 305)
  - Wilson, Reuel K., 1979, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 306)
  - Wilson, Rosalind Baker (to Epstein, Jason), 1972 Jul 16 (Box 8, Folder 307)
  - Wilson, Rosalind Baker (to Wilson, Susan Colston) (Box 8, Folder 308)
  - Wilson, Susan Colston
    See: Wilson, Rosalind Baker, box 8, folder 308
  - Winkelhorn, Sofka, 1976-79 (Box 8, Folder 309)
  - Wolfe, Bertram D., 1972, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 310)
    Includes Wolfe, Ella
  - Yadin, Yigael, 1973-78 (Box 8, Folder 311)
  - Yoken, Melvin B., 1972 May-Nov (Box 8, Folder 312)
  - Young, Andrew, 1978 Aug 25 (Box 8, Folder 313)
  - Unidentified, 1972-79, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 314-315)
- Writings, 1971-1979; Series II; 7.71; (19 boxes)
  - LETTERS ON LITERATURE AND POLITICS
    - Background Materials
      - Card file index of Edmund Wilson correspondents (Box 9, Folder 316)
      - Lists of Edmund Wilson correspondents (Box 10, Folder 317-318)
      - Edmund Wilson biographical chronologies (Box 10, Folder 319)
      - Other notes, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 320)
    - Photocopies of Edmund Wilson Correspondence
      - Aaron, Daniel (1952-71, n.d.) (Box 10, Folder 321)
      - Adams, Leonie (1940, n.d.) (Box 10, Folder 322)
      - Aiken, Conrad (1954), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 323)
      - Alsop, Joseph Wright (1970 Feb-Jun), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 324)
        Typed transcripts
      - Anderson, Margaret C. (1952 Mar 20) (Box 10, Folder 325)
      - Anderson, Sherwood (1926-46) (Box 10, Folder 326)
        Includes Anderson, Eleanor
      - Arbasino, Alberto (1961), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 327)
      - Arvin, Newton (1932-62), 1973, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 328)
      - Atlantic Monthly Press (1958-70, n.d.), 1974, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 329)
      - Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh) (1947 Oct 9), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 330)
      - Austin, John E. (1957), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 331)
        See also: Dabney, Lewis M., box 13, folder 397
      - Ballot, Jeanne (1947-72, n.d.) (Box 10, Folder 332)
      - Barnes, Djuna (1965 Oct-Nov), 1974, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 333)
      - Barrett, William
        See: Partisan Review, box 19, folder 546
      - Basso, Hamilton (1927-62), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 334)
      - Becker, Mr. (1937), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 335)
      - Behrman, S. N. (Samuel Nathaniel) (1951, n.d.) (Box 10, Folder 336)
      - Belknap, Morris (1916-27, n.d.) (Box 10, Folder 337)
      - Bellinger, Alfred Raymond (1912-13) (Box 10, Folder 338-340)
      - Bellinger, Alfred Raymond (1913-18, n.d.) (Box 11, Folder 341-346)
      - Benet, William Rose (1928-49), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 347)
      - Berryman, John (1940-59), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 348)
      - Biggs, John (1941-52, n.d.) (Box 11, Folder 349-350)
      - Bishop, Alison (1966-71), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 351)
      - Bishop, John Peale (1919-44), 1974, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 352-355)
      - Bishop, Jonathan
        See: Bishop, Alison, box 11, folder 351
      - Blackmur, Richard P. (1929-46), 1974, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 356)
      - Bliven, Bruce
        See: The New Republic, box 18, folder 534
      - Blumberg, Henry D. (1968 Jul), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 357)
      - Bogan, Louise (1931-68, n.d.) (Box 12, Folder 358-360)
        Includes Holden, Raymond
      - Bowen, Elizabeth (1950 Oct 25), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 361)
      - Bowers, Fredson (1969 Jan-Apr), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 362)
      - Boyd, Julian P. (1945-46), 1974, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 363)
      - [Boyd, -----?] (1934 Apr 2), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 364)
      - Braithwaite, William Stanley (1921-22), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 365)
      - Brandon, Henry (1958-62, n.d.) (Box 12, Folder 366)
      - Brinnin, John Malcolm (1940 No 12), 1975 (Box 12, Folder 367)
        Typed transcript
      - Brooks, Cleanth
        See: Warren, Robert Penn, box 21, folder 609
      - Brooks, Van Wyck (1921-63), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 368)
        Includes Brooks, Gladys
      - Brown, E. K. (Edward Killoran) (1942-47), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 369)
      - Bruccoli, Matthew Joseph (1964 Nov 25), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 370)
      - Burke, Kenneth (1923, n.d.) (Box 12, Folder 371)
      - Burnett, Whit (1942-47, n.d.), 1974, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 372)
      - Bynner, Witter (1950-51), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 373)
      - Cabell, James Branch (1955-56), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 374)
      - Cairns, Huntington (1947 Jul 26), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 375)
      - Callaghan, Morley (1955-69), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 376)
      - Calverton, V. F. (Victor Francis) (1930-36, n.d.) (Box 12, Folder 377)
      - Carroll, Clelia (1961-71, n.d.) (Box 12, Folder 378-380)
        Includes a photocopy of Holiday Greetings and Desolating Lyrics from Edmund Wilson (1970)
      - Cerf, Bennet (1933), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 381)
      - Chapman, John Jay (1927-31), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 382)
        See also: Howe, Mark De Wolfe, box 15, folder 461
      - Charles Scribner's Sons (n.d.) (Box 12, Folder 383)
        See also: Perkins, Maxwell E. (Maxwell Evarts), box 19, folders 549-550
      - Chavchavadze, Nina (1945 Jun 7), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 384)
        Original TLS
      - Clynes, Edmund (1964-71) (Box 12, Folder 385)
        Includes original TLS to EC from Mary McCarthy
      - Coates, Robert M. (Robert Myron) (1930 Aug 20), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 386)
      - Collins, Seward (1923-29), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 387)
      - Colt Press
        See: Grabhorn, Jane Bissell, box 14, folder 447
      - Colum, Mary (1923-63), 1973, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 388)
        Includes Colum, Padraic
      - Columbia University (1938-53), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 389)
      - Cowles, Mrs. (1955-56, n.d.) (Box 12, Folder 390)
      - Cowley, Malcolm (1923-58, n.d.) (Box 12, Folder 391-392)
      - Creece, James (1918 May 3), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 393)
      - Cross, Wilbur (1928 Jan 16), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 394)
      - Crosten, Loran (1966-71), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 395)
        Includes Crosten, Mary
      - Cummings, E. E. (Edward Estlin) (1926-45, n.d.) (Box 13, Folder 396)
      - Dabney, Lewis M. (1957-62), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 397)
      - Dahlberg, Edward (1954 Mar-Nov), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 398)
      - Davison, Peter (1958 Jun 13), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 399)
        See also: Atlantic Monthly Press, box 10, folder 329
        See also: Aaron, Daniel, box 10, folder 321
      - Dell, Floyd (1952-53), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 400)
      - Dell, W. Stanley (1915-71), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 401-403)
      - Deming, Barbara (1959-62), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 404)
        Includes original TLS and typed transcripts
      - Deutsch, Babette (1936-69), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 405)
        See also: Yarmolinsky, Avraham, box 21, folder 626
      - The Dial, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 406)
        Notes only
        See also: Burke, Kenneth, box 12, folder 371
        See also: Gregory, Alyse, box 14, folder 448
        See also: Moore, Marianne, box 16, folder 507
      - Didion, Joan (1971 Oct 25), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 407)
      - Dos Passos, John (1932-70, n.d.) (Box 13, Folder 408-411)
        Includes Dos Passos, Katherine Includes Dos Passos, Elizabeth Hamlin Holdridge
      - Draper, Muriel (1929-39, n.d.) (Box 13, Folder 412)
      - Dreiser, Theodore (1932-53, n.d.) (Box 13, Folder 413)
        Includes Elias, Robert H.
      - Dupee, F. W. (Frederick Wilcox) (1938-66), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 414)
        See also: Partisan Review, box 19, folder 546
      - Eastman, Max (1933-54), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 415)
      - Edel, Leon (1952-68, n.d.) (Box 13, Folder 416)
      - Edmonds, Walter Dumaux (1962-71) (Box 13, Folder 417)
      - Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns) (1923-46), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 418)
      - Ellmann, Richard (1967 Jan 31), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 419)
      - Epstein, Barbara (1963-72), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 420)
      - Epstein, Jason (1961-69), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 421)
      - Ernst, Morris Leopold (1937 Dec 22), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 422)
      - Farrar, Straus & Giroux
        See: Peck, John B., box 19, folder 547
        See: Straus, Roger W., box 20, folders 585-586
      - Farrell, James T. (1936-40), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 423)
        Includes Farrell, Hortense Alden
      - Fassett, Agatha (1963 Jun 26), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 424)
      - Faulkner, William (1956-58), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 425)
      - Felstiner, John (1969 Oct 31), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 426)
      - Fenton, William Nelson (1957-71), 1974, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 427)
        Includes Fenton, Olive
      - Fitzgerald, F. Scott (Francis Scott) (1915-40, n.d.), 1974, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 428-429)
      - Fitzgerald, Zelda (1940 Dec 27), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 430)
      - Flanner, Janet (1958 Nov 21), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 431)
      - Flory, Margaret A., n.d. (Box 14, Folder 432)
      - Ford, Ford Madox (1932 Oct 13), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 433)
      - Frank, Waldo (1932-61), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 434)
      - Frankfurter, Felix (1953-61), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 435)
      - Friedman, B. H. (1961 Sep-Dec), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 436)
      - Gardner, Helen (1945-63), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 437)
      - Gates, Sylvester (1927-60, n.d.) (Box 14, Folder 438)
      - Gauss, Christian Frederick (1918-56, n.d.), 1974, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 439-442)
        Includes Jackson, Katherine Gauss (typed transcripts)
      - Geismar, Maxwell David (1941-53, n.d.), 1973-74, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 443-444)
        Includes Katz, Florine
      - Gibbs, Wolcott
        See: The New Yorker, box 18, folders 536-538
      - Goetz, George
        See: Calverton, V. F. (Victor Francis), box 12, folder 377
      - Goodman, Celia (1947-71, n.d.) (Box 14, Folder 445)
      - Gordon, Mr. (1941 Oct), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 446)
      - Gotham Book Mart
        See: Steloff, Frances, box 20, folder 583
      - Grabhorn, Jane Bissell (1943-49), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 447)
      - Gramercy Book Shop
        See: Columbia University, box 12, folder 389
      - Gregory, Alyse (1924-52), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 448)
      - Gulick, Alice M. (1960 Sep 17), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 449)
      - Hackett, Chauncey (1940-60, n.d.), 1974, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 450)
        Includes original ALS and TLS
      - Harper [Mr.?] (1917 Mar 17), 1974, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 451)
      - Harris, Julian LaRose (1951-57), 1978, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 452)
      - Hart-Davis, Rupert (1965-71), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 453)
        Includes typed transcripts
      - Hawthorne, Hazel (1927-52), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 454)
        Includes Werner, M. R. (Morris Robert)
      - Hecht, Anthony (1967 Jan 31), 1974 (Box 15, Folder 455)
      - Hemingway, Ernest (1927, Jan-May, n.d.), 1974, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 456)
      - Herkimer County Historical Society
        See: Blumberg, Henry D., box 11, folder 357
      - Herzog, Lily (1949-68), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 457)
      - Highet, Gilbert (1949-52), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 458)
      - Horgan, Paul (1966-71, n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 459)
      - Houghton Mifflin Company (1945 Jan 3), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 460)
      - Howe, Mark De Wolfe (1935-38), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 461)
      - Huebsch, Benjamin K. (1925-53), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 462)
      - Huling, Elizabeth (1941-68), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 463)
      - Humphries, Rolfe (1927-43), 1975, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 464)
      - Jackson, Katherine Gauss
        See: Gauss, Christian Frederick, box 14, folders 439-442
      - Johnson, Richard Colles (1967 May), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 465)
      - Joyce, James (1928 Jul 23), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 466)
      - Kazin, Alfred (1942-70), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 467)
      - Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald) (1963 Apr-Nov), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 468)
      - Kenton, Edna (1925 Oct), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 469)
      - Kern, Edith (1962, n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 470)
      - Kirstein, Lincoln (1929-34), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 471)
      - Kline, George (1959 Aug 12), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 472)
      - Koestler, Mamaine (1945-54), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 473-477)
      - Kretzoi, Charlotte (1964-70, n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 478)
      - Kriegel, Leonard (1971 Nov), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 479)
      - Kronenburger, Louis (1947-65), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 480)
      - Landau, Jacob (1956-69, n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 481)
      - Lang, Cecil Y. (1960-69, n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 482)
      - Levin, Harry (1939-68), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 483)
        Includes Zarudnaya, Elena
      - Lewis, Wyndham (1941 Nov-Dec) (Box 16, Folder 484)
      - Linscott, Robert Newton (1931-62), 1973-79, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 485)
      - Lippmann, Walter (1920-30), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 486)
      - The Listener (1956 Oct-Nov), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 487)
      - Loos, Anita (1966-70), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 488)
      - Lowell, Robert (1959-61), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 489)
      - Mabbott, Thomas Olive (1958 Jan 19), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 490)
      - MacDonald, Dwight
      - McFee, William (1946 Oct 10), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 491)
      - MacKenzie, Compton (1958 Aug 18), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 492)
      - MacLennan, Hugh (1964-68), 1974, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 493)
      - McWilliams, Carey (1929-32), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 494)
      - Manning, Robert
        See: Atlantic Monthly Press, box 10, folder 329
      - Marshall, Margaret (1947-67), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 495)
      - Matthews, T. S. (Thomas Stanley) (1960-68), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 496)
      - Matthiessen, F. O. (Francis Otto) (1944-47, n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 497)
      - Maxwell, William
        See: The New Yorker, box 18, folder 536-538
      - Mebane, Daniel
      - Mele, Bette Crouse (1960-71), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 498)
      - Mellquist, Jerome (1935-48), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 499)
      - Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis) (1921-47, n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 500-501)
        Includes a photocopy of Three Reliques of Ancient Western Poetry, by Edmund Wilson
      - Milford, Nancy Winston (1968 Jan 22), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 502)
      - Millay, Norma (1952 Jan 31), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 503)
      - Mizener, Arthur (1943-59), 1976, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 504-505)
      - Modern Monthly
      - Monroe, Harriet (1919-20), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 506)
      - Moore, Marianne (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 507)
      - More, Paul Elmer (1933 Apr 22), 1974, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 508)
      - Morris, Glyn (1964-72, n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 509)
        Includes Morris, Gladys Includes [Erwin?], Barbara
      - Muchnic, Helen (1942-53), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 510-511)
      - Muchnic, Helen (1955-72, n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 512-515)
        Includes McCarthy, Mary Includes Walsh, Dorothy
      - Muste, Abraham John (1937-65), 1974, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 516)
      - Nabokov, Vladimir (1940-49), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 517-525)
        Includes Nabokova, Vera
      - Nabokov, Vladimir (1950-71, n.d.) (Box 18, Folder 526-531)
      - Nevins, Allan (1928-53), n.d. (Box 18, Folder 532)
      - Nevius, Blake (1953 Jul-Aug), n.d. (Box 18, Folder 533)
      - The New Republic (1934-37, n.d.) (Box 18, Folder 534)
      - New Statesman
        See: Faulkner, William, box 13, folder 425
      - New York Review of Books (1966-[72], n.d.) (Box 18, Folder 535)
        See also: Epstein, Barbara, box 13, folder 420
      - The New Yorker (1929-72, n.d.) (Box 18, Folder 536-538)
        Includes lists of editorial personnel, 1969 and 1970
        See also: Ross, Harold, box 19, folder 564
        See also: Walden, Harriet, box 21, folder 607
      - Nisbet, Ada (1952-69), n.d. (Box 18, Folder 539)
      - Nomad, Max (1953-69, n.d.) (Box 18, Folder 540)
      - Norton, W. W.
        See: W. W. Norton & Company, box 21, folder 605
      - Noyes, Larry G.
        See: Troxell, Gilbert, box 20, folder 599
      - O'Donnell, Thomas Francis (1962-70), n.d. (Box 18, Folder 541)
      - Oliver, Edith
      - Orwell, George (1948 Jan 10), n.d. (Box 18, Folder 542)
      - Ourossow, Eugenie (1959-71), n.d. (Box 18, Folder 543)
      - Oxford University Press (1947-69, n.d.) (Box 19, Folder 544-545)
      - Partisan Review (1937-49, n.d.) (Box 19, Folder 546)
      - Peck, John B. (1972, n.d.) (Box 19, Folder 547)
        See also: Straus, Roger W., box 20, folders 585-586
      - Perelman, S. J. (Sidney Joseph) (1958, 1963), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 548)
      - Perkins, Maxwell E. (Maxwell Evarts) (1928-50), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 549-550)
        Includes Wheelock, John Hall
      - Perowne, Stewart (1969 Jan 24), 1974, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 551)
      - Phillips, William
      - Poetry: A Magazine of Verse (1939-40), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 552)
      - Powell, Dawn (1943-65, n.d.) (Box 19, Folder 553)
      - Praz, Mario (1951-62), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 554)
      - Preston, John Hyde (1928 Jun 25), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 555)
      - Pritchett, V. S. (Victor Sawdon) (1970 Mar-Jun), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 556)
      - Putnam, Phelps (1927-39), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 557)
      - Random House (publisher)
        See: Cerf, Bennett, box 12, folder 381
      - Rascoe, Burton (1924-57), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 558)
        Includes Rascoe, Hazel
      - Reed, Joseph W. (1965-67), 1975, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 559)
      - Roditi, Edouard (1944 Mar 10), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 560)
      - Roellinger, Francis X. (1949 Apr 1), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 561)
        Original ALS
      - Rorem, Ned (1959 Dec 31), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 562)
      - Rose, William K. (1960 Apr-Jun), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 563)
      - Ross, Harold (1929-43), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 564)
      - Rovere, Richard Halworth (1958 May 16), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 565)
      - Rullman, Margaret A. (1950-71), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 566)
      - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr. (1944-64), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 567)
        Includes Schlesinger, Marian Cannon
      - Schneider, Cyril M. (1952 Mar 19), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 568)
      - Schouvaloff, Elisabeth (1955, 1965), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 569)
        Original ALS and TLS
      - Schwerin, Mr. (1960 Jul 19), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 570)
      - Scribner, Mr. (1952 Aug 24), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 571)
      - Scribner's Magazine (1922-25), 1974, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 572)
      - Segal, Erich (1971 Sep 19), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 573)
      - Seldes, Gilbert (1923-68), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 574)
      - Shafter, Miss (1957 May 13), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 575)
      - Shawn, William (1944-72, n.d.) (Box 20, Folder 576)
        See also: The New Yorker, box 18, folders 536-538
      - Sheed, Wilfrid (1969 Apr 25), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 577)
      - Sinclair, Upton (1925-57), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 578)
        Includes Sinclair, Mary Craig
      - Singer, Issac Bashevis (1967 Jan 31), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 579)